Finding Aid for Harvey Ovshinsky papers, 1948-2014
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Project Files
  - Educational and Children's Properties
    - Pendragon's Fire and Pendragon's Park
      - Presentations, 2003-2011
        - Miscellaneous, 2003-2011 (Box 5)
    - Please Don't Eat the Books
      - Correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box 5)
        Concerning NOGGIN Network
      - Personal notes and business plan, 2001 (Box 5)
      - Creative notes, circa 2001-2002; 5 folders (Box 5)
        Folder 1 includes original drawings
      - Pilot script drafts, 2001 (Box 5)
      - Legal, 2001-2003 (Box 5)
      - Topical files on the history of books and writing, 2001-2011 (Box 5)
    - The Mighty Hubble
      Project for Family Communications Inc.
      - Creative concepts
        - Greenlight Gardens, 1997-2000; 2001 (Box 6)
        - 2006-2007, 3 folders (Box 6)
        - 2007, 7 folders (Box 6)
        - 2008, 2 folders (Box 6)
      - Visual concepts, undated; 5 folders (Box 6)
      - Research materials on child psychology and play, circa, 2006-2007; 7 folders (Box 6)
      - War Dance, 2006-2008 (Box 6)
      - Legal, 2006-2008 (Box 6)
      - Content guidelines for Family Communications Inc., 2006-2008 (Box 6)
        1 of 3 folders
      - Content guidelines for Family Communications Inc., 2006-2008 (Box 7)
        2 of 3 folders
      - Feedback from content consultants, 2006-2008 (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous Unproduced Projects and Properties
    - Mumford Music, 1989-2011 (Box 7)
    - We Were Central, circa 2005 (Box 7)
    - Taxi Dancer, circa 2002 (Box 7)
    - Darrow and Sweet, circa 1987-1988 (Box 7)
    - Noah and His Totally Awesome Ark, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
    - Do You See What I See, 2001 (Box 7)
    - Moolah, Moolah, undated (Box 7)
    - Leonardo's Kitchen, undated (Box 7)
    - The New Adventures of the Bold Fontz, 2008-2009 (Box 7)
    - Aggie's Farm, 2007 (Box 7)
    - Tank Tales, 2001 (Box 7)
    - Always Christmas, 2001 (Box 7)
    - Mammoth, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Darby Winton's Diary, undated (Box 7)
    - Coming Home and Reunion, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Robert's Ranch, 2007 (Box 7)
    - The Watermarks and The Lady Chatterley, circa 1988 (Box 7)
    - Wanda the White Butterfly, 1994 (Box 7)
    - The Littlest Maccabee, undated (Box 7)
    - 2nd Helpings and Mrs. Koogle's Kitchen, 2001 (Box 7)
    - The Sunfire Gang, circa 1980-1986 (Box 7)
      (Includes photographs)
    - Meet the Plushies, circa 2009 (Box 7)
    - Collaborations, circa 2001 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous ideas, circa 2004 (Box 7)
    - Dodge Brothers
      - Chrysler Brand History Documentary Materials, 1998 (Box 7)
      - War Dance, 1999 (Box 7)
      - Biographical sketches, circa, 1997-1999 (Box 8)
      - Topical files, circa, 1997-2010 (Box 8)
        3 of 4 folders
      - Topical files, circa, 1997-2010 (Box 14)
        4 of 4 folders
      - Outlines, creative notes and drafts, with gaps, circa 1999-2008; 5 folders (Box 8)
      - Proposal, 2008 (Box 8)
- Audiovisual materials
  The Audiovisual materials series (4 linear feet, 1969-2009) provides a sample of Ovshinsky's work in radio, television, and children's educational programming. These recordings include Spare Change, Barrington Bunny, ABX News, and Pendragon's Park. This series also includes a video recording of the PAH Festival Keynote from 2009, a talk listed in the Speaking engagements, presentations, and workshops group in the Professional files series. Ovshinsky's item level inventory of the content in the Audiovisual materials series is also included in the series.
  - WRIF Spare Change Morning Talk Show, 1969-1970; 8 audiotapes 7 in. reel-to-reel (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous radio programs, undated; 21 audiotapes 7-in. reel-to-reels (Box 10)
  - HKO/ABX News, undated; 1 audiotapes 10.5-in. reel-to-reel (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous radio programs, with gaps, 1980(?)-1995; 25 audiocassettes (Box 11)
  - Barrington Bunny, 1974; 1 reels 16mm film reel; 1 videotapes Beta SP tape (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous videos
    - With gaps, 1974-2005; 29 videotapes Sony DVCAM videocassettes (Box 11)
    - The Deer Hunters, 1983; .ZIP and .MP4 files
    - 1985-2003, 36 videotapes 23 Sony DVCAM videocassettes and 13 Beta SP videocassettes (Box 12)
  - Pendragon's Park, 2002; 11 videotapes Beta SP videocassettes (Box 13)
  - Public Appearances, Workshops and Presentations
    - 1983-2009, 10 videotapes Sony DVCAM videocassettes (Box 13)
    - "Career Day with Harvey Ovshinsky", undated; .ZIP file
Related Materials
The Bentley Historical Library holds the papers of John and Leni Sinclair, who helped Ovshinsky with the creation of early issues of The Fifth Estate. The finding aid for the John and Leni Sinclair papers can be found online at http://quod.lib.umich.edu/b/bhlead/umich-bhl-850. There are five folders in the "Pre-1978" subseries of the "Writings" Series containing Sinclair's columns for The Fifth Estate.
The University of Michigan Special Collections Library also has a collection of Fifth Estate records dating from 1967-2003. The catalog record for this collection is available online at http://mirlyn.lib.umich.edu/Record/004312744.